ariasystems.net 2008-05-09

# Privacy Policy | Aria Systems

The personal information we collect from you will be used by Aria to provide the service or carry out the transaction you have requested or authorized. This may include using the personal information for the following purposes: 

  * To provide you with important information about the product or service that you are using; 
  * To make a site or service easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the site or service to your particular interests or preferences; 
  * To improve the product or service and to provide better customer service to users. 

The privacy statement of the specific product or service you are using will disclose how the personal information that is collected will be used. 

Aria does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Aria may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as packaging. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. 

Aria may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Aria or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Aria and its family of web sites, and, (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Aria, its web sites, or the public. 

Personally identifiable information collected by Aria may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Aria maintains facilities. 

### U.S. - EU Safe Harbor Privacy Statement

For personal information of employees, consumers, healthcare professionals, medical research subjects and investigators, customers, investors, and government officials that Aria receives from the European Economic Area, Aria has committed to handling such personal information in accordance with the Safe Harbor Principles. Aria's Safe Harbor certification can be found on the [Safe Harbor Lists](http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/shlist.nsf/webPages/safe+harbor+list). For more information about the Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Website at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/sh_overview.html>.

### Controlling and Accessing Your Personal Information

Aria believes that you should be able to exercise control over how the personal information you provide will be used. If you provide personal information to Aria for one purpose, you will be able to opt-out of that personal information being used for other unrelated purposes. 

Please be aware that the choices you make in one context will not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to Aria in the context of other, separately operated, Aria products, sites or services.

### Security of Your Personal Information 

Aria carefully protects the security of the personal information you provide. Personal information we collect is stored in password-controlled servers with limited access, and we protect this information from loss or misuse, and from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. When sensitive personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted over the Internet, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

### Use of Cookies On Aria Sites 

In some cases, Aria's web site uses "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you or your computer, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize an Aria web page, or register with an Aria site or service, a cookie helps us to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Aria web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. While some cookies contain personal information, others allow you to customize a site while remaining anonymous. The privacy statement of the particular site you are visiting will describe how that site uses cookies. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. However, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the sites or services you visit. 

### Contact Information 

At Aria, we work hard to protect your privacy. Our privacy principles represent our commitment to ensuring that your personal information is safe and secure. If you believe that Aria has not adhered to these policies, please contact us by e-mail or postal mail, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
